Guide to the Picture File, 1700s-1980s and undated RL.01025
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Geographic Series, 1700s-1980s; 1
  - France, 18
    - Exposition Universelle de 1889. - Tour Eiffel, Restaurant Russe, 1889, black-and-white photograph (Box 47)
    - Marseille oder Marisilan [German], 1700s?, black-and-white illustration (Box 37)
    - Paris - French Armored Cars, circa 1940s, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M122)
    - Paris, Prise Du Pont D'Austerlitz, undated, lithograph (Box 4, Folder M123)
    - Prop. de l'Eglise St. Martin de Champs, 1700s?, black-and-white illustration (Box 37)
    - Reims la Pompelle, Berry-au-Bac en Ruines. After The Bombardment, after 1914, viewbook (Box 4, Folder M124)
    - Scene by painter Simon Lantara, reproduction drawing by Bordea (?), 1800s?, watercolor (Box 57)
      Medium is uncertain.
  - Georgia, 19
    - "A View of Savannah As It Stood The 29th of March, 1734," undated, engraving (Box 47)
    - [Athens] "Franklin College in Athens, Georgia," 1800s, photocopy of newsprint (Box 4, Folder M125)
    - [Athens] "University of Georgia Views," 1926 July, viewbook (Box 4, Folder M126)
      Contains 35 black-and-white photographic illustrations, some with descriptive notes.
    - [Augusta] "City Hall," circa 1831, 4 engravings (Box 4, Folder M132)
      Two color and two black-and-white versions of same engraving.
    - [Augusta] "Embryo Town of Columbus on the Chatahoochee," 1800s, engraving (Box 4, Folder M135)
    - [Augusta] "Great Flood," 1888 Sept. 10-11, 5 card photographs (Box 4, Folder M133)
    - [Augusta] "In Remembrance of the School Year 1883," Richmond Academy, First Class, undated, card photograph (Box 4, Folder M127)
      Transferred from the Charles Edgeworth Jones Papers.
    - [Augusta] "St. Paul's Church Dating From Colonial Times," undated, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 4, Folder M128)
      Where remains of Lt. Gen. L. Polk rest.
    - [Chatahoochee River] "Lover's Leap," 1800s, engraving (Box 4, Folder M137)
    - [Crawfordville] "Liberty Hall, Residence of Alexander H. Stephens," 1868, 2 engravings (Box 4, Folder M130)
      [From Alexander H. Stephens' "A Constitutional View of the War Between the States..." Vol. 1; transferred from Marmaduke Floyd Collection.]
    - [La Grange] "Brownwood Female Institute," 1844 June, 2 engravings (Box 4, Folder M140)
      From Grahams Magazine. Duplicate image.
    - [Macon] "Georgia Female College," circa 1840, engraving (Box 4, Folder M142)
    - [Midway] "Oglethorpe University," circa 1840s, 2 engravings (Box 4, Folder M144)
      From Grahams Magazine.
    - [Oxcart] team in Savannah, circa 1910, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M162.2)
    - "A View of Savannah As It Stood The 29th of March, 1734," undated, color engraving (Box 4, Folder M159)
    - "A View of Savannah From The River," 1800s, engraving (Box 4, Folder M160)
    - [Savannah] "At Grand Prize Races," circa 1914, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M147)
    - [Savannah] "Hermitage" slave huts, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M152)
      Includes note telling why these huts are not "East Hermitage." From the Manigault Family Papers, Vol. IV, Southern Historical Collection, UNC-CH.
    - [Savannah] "Pulaski Monument - Episcopal Church," circa 1840s, engraving (Box 4, Folder M155)
    - [Savannah] "Telfair Academy Of Arts And Sciences," 1920, paper illustration (Box 4, Folder M157)
    - "The Great Savanna Fire Of 1820...," undated, engraving (Box 4, Folder M151)
    - [Savannah] Fort Pulaski, after 1860, 3 card photographs (Box 37)
    - [Savannah] Local scenes, circa 1883-1936, 34 black-and-white photographs and 4 card photographs (Box 4, Folder M153)
    - [Savannah] Old Cemetery, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M154)
    - [Savannah] Savannah views, undated, 1 lithograph, 1 engraving and 6 sketches (Box 4, Folder M161)
    - View of Savannah, undated, clipping (Box 4, Folder M158)
    - A View of Savannah, GA as it stood the 29th of March 1734, undated, color engraving (Oversize-folder 46)
    - Ars Carolina, early 1800s?, black-and-white illustration (Box 37)
      From "Johnson: Sketches of...Nathanael Greene."
    - Branch of the United States Bank, Savannah, 1831 Oct. 15, engraving (Box 4, Folder M148)
    - Burning of Savannah, published by M. Carey and Son, Philadelphia, 1800s, with sheet of text, engraving (Box 37)
      Includes a description of the Savannah fire of Jan. 11, 1820.
    - City of Columbus, circa 1840, engraving (Box 4, Folder M129)
    - City of Savannah, 1876, engraving (Box 4, Folder M149)
    - Columbus, Augusta, and Macon, sketched by Theodore R. Davis, 1868 Sept. 19, clipping (Box 37)
      Clipping taken from "Harper's Weekly." Negative of Macon available.
    - Confederate Veterans in front of Oglethorpe Club, Savannah, circa 1910, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M162.2)
    - Falls of Toccoa, 1844, engraving (Box 5, Folder M163)
    - Fort Caroline, 1847, engraving (Box 4, Folder M139)
      [From William Bacon Stevens' "A History of Georgia," Vol. 1]
    - Georgia. Chatham County, 1816, map (Box 38)
      View of Cedar Grove settlement, the seat of Abraham, Esquire
    - Gunboats Entering Savannah River Above Fort Pulaski, circa 1860s (Box 4, Folder M156)
    - Lithia Springs Spa, 1800s, card photograph (Box 4, Folder M141)
    - Lithia Springs Spa, 1800s, card photograph (Box 43)
    - Log House in the Forests of Georgia, 1800s, engraving (Box 4, Folder M136)
    - Medical College of Georgia, 1844, 2 engravings (Box 4, Folder M143)
      From "Grahams Magazine."
    - Members of Georgia Hussars with African American prisoner at Clyde, Ga. in 1908(?) to prevent lynching of prisoner. (Box 4, Folder M162.1)
      This man afterwards died of tuberculosis and syphilis in Chatham County jail while awaiting a new trial on appeal.
    - Methodist Ministers at Savannah, circa 1910, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M162.2)
    - Motorcycle and horse races in Savannah, circa 1910, 8 black-and-white photographs (Box 4, Folder M162.3)
    - Old Pirates House, East Broad and Wright Streets, Savannah GA, 1946, black-and-white watercolor (Oversize-folder 11)
      Original painting by Harriet Cann.
    - Oxcart team in Savannah, 1888, album print (Box 4, Folder M162.4)
    - Plan of the Town Ebenezer and its Fort, 1800s, engraving (Box 4, Folder M131)
    - Rock Mountain, 1844-1845, 2 engravings (Box 4, Folder M145)
    - Savannah motorized fire equipment, circa 1910, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M162.2)
    - Savannah physicians, circa 1910, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M162.2)
    - Savannah, 1790-1915, courtesy of Southern Savings and Loan, circa 1915, 2 engravings (Box 43)
    - Slave cabins at the Hermitage, near Savannah, circa 1910 (Box 4, Folder M162.1)
    - Steam Ship 'Savannah' -- Capt. Moses Rogers, 1819 Mar. 28 (Box 4, Folder M156)
    - Stone Mountain, Georgia, early 1800s, lithograph (Box 37)
    - The Expedition In Warsaw Sound, 1800s (Box 4, Folder M156)
    - The First Flag of the Independence Raised in the South, by the Citizens of Savannah, Ga., November 8th, 1860, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 4, Folder M150)
      Photograph of a lithograph that was originally in the Georgia Portfolio II.
    - The Georgia Militia Under Gen. Floyd, Attacking the Creek Indians at Autossee - Nov. 29, 1813, circa 1931, black-and-white photograph (Box 44)
      From an engraving.
    - The Old Pirate House, Savannah, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 38)
    - The Rebel Flag Of Truce Boats Coming Down The Savannah River..., circa 1860s (Box 4, Folder M156)
    - The Steamship 'Savanna' - 1819, undated (Box 4, Folder M156)
    - Two Slave Drivers and a Backwoodsman With His Rifle, 1800s, engraving (Box 4, Folder M138)
    - View of Public Square, Atlanta, Georgia, 1864, color lithograph (Oversize-folder 28)
    - View of Rome, Georgia, 1800s, clipping (Box 4, Folder M146)
    - Vue Du Port De Savanna, 1700s (Box 4, Folder M156)
  - Germany, 20
    - [Dresden] "Das Alte Rathhaus...," 1708, lithograph (Box 37)
    - [Dresden] "Das Königliche Schloss...," 1756, lithograph (Box 37)
    - [Dresden] "Der Neumarkt Um Das Jahr 1750," 1750, lithograph (Box 37)
    - [Frankfurt] "Die Franckfurther Brücke über den Maÿn...," 1700s?, lithograph (Box 37)
    - [Ingolstadt] "Ingolstadt so A: 1632 von dem Konige aus Schweden...," 1632?, lithograph (Box 37)
    - [Königliche] "Grofses Concert der Königl. Hofkapelle...," 1812 May 24, lithograph (Box 37)
    - [Metz] "Metz -- Eine von denen Dreÿen...," 1700?, lithograph (Box 37)
    - [Oberammergau] Passion Play, 1870, 5 card photographs (Box 5, Folder M165)
    - [Regensburg] "Die Donaw Brück zu Regenspurg," 1700s?, lithograph (Box 37)
    - [Rotenberg] "Der Rothe-Berg Beÿ 4. Stund von Nürmberg gelegen," 1700s?, lithograph (Box 37)
    - [Ulm] "Ulm gegen Sud Osten," 1700s?, lithograph (Box 37)
    - Coburg, undated, lithograph (Box 37)
    - Relief Panorama des Rheines in Kupferdruck, circa 1900, map (Box 5, Folder M166)
  - Greece, 21
    - [Athens - Dionysus theatre], 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 5, Folder M167)
    - [Athens] "Theatre at Delphi," 1900s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 5, Folder M168)
  - Haiti
    - Marketplace in Gonaïves, 1928 (Box 5, Folder M1826)
      2 black and white photographs
  - India, 22
    - [Agra] Taj Mahal - under construction, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 5, Folder M173)
    - [Jhansi] Individuals demonstrating the power of mind over matter, 1900s, 8 black-and-white photographs (Box 5, Folder M174)
    - Agra market, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 5, Folder M169)
    - Ajmer potterymaking, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 5, Folder M172)
    - Bombay market, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 5, Folder M171)
    - Jaipur market, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 5, Folder M170)
    - Lucknow ruins, undated, 3 photographs (Box 5, Folder M175)
  - Indonesia, 23
    - Java market and transportation, undated, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 5, Folder M182)
  - Italy, 24
    - [Bologna] Seal of the University of Bologna, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 5, Folder M176)
    - Florence - souvenir photograph collection, circa 1920s, 20 black-and-white photographs (Box 5, Folder M177)
      Includes original paper envelope
    - Monte Trinita oder der Berg zu Heyl Dreyfaltigkeit zu Gaeta, undated, engraving (Box 5, Folder M178)
    - Pignerol, 1600s, engraving (Box 5, Folder M179)
    - [Rome] Altra veduta di dentro di S. Maria Della Pace, restaurata et adornata da N.S. Papa Alessandro VII, 18th century?, black-and-white engraving (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Sicilian temple at Segesta, Sicily, circa 1840, colored engraving (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Splendid marble pulpit in Messina Cathedral, Sicily, circa 1840, colored engraving (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Terracina, Italy, undated, engraving (Box 47)
  - Japan, 25
    - Japan Today - A Collection of Photographs by Germaine Kellerman - 1941, after 1941, 47 black-and-white photographs (Box 5, Folder M180)
    - Tokyo - old gold tower, undated, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 5, Folder M181)
      Emulsion flaking - handle with care.
  - Kentucky, 26
    - [Covington] "Western Baptist Theological Institute," 1841, engraving (Box 5, Folder M185)
    - [Forest Retreat] "Gov. Metcalfe's Residence," 1800s, lithograph (Box 5, Folder M186)
    - [Jonesville] "George Kean House," undated, card photograph (Box 5, Folder M187)
    - [Lexington] "View of Insane Asylum," 1800s, lithograph (Box 5, Folder M188)
    - Augusta College, 1800s, lithograph (Box 5, Folder M183)
    - City of Louisville, 1872, color engraving (Box 37)
    - Coat of Arms of Kentucky, 1800s, engraving (Box 5, Folder M184)
    - Main House at Shaker Village, 1800s, lithograph (Box 5, Folder M189)
    - The Homestead of Henry Clay, 1853, black-and-white engraving (Oversize-folder 11)
      Front view of house, Negative attached.
  - Korea, 27
    - Glimpses of Chosen, circa 1930s, 2 viewbooks (Box 5, Folder M190)
      Chosen is another word for "Korea."
  - Louisiana, 28
    - [New Orleans] "French Cemetery" and "Representation of the Exchange Hotel," 1800s, 2 clippings (Box 5, Folder M191)
    - [New Orleans] Custom House and French Market, 1800s, 2 card photographs (Box 5, Folder M191)
    - [New Orleans] Side vaults or ovens, Old St. Louis Cemetery, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 5, Folder M191)
    - Louisiana - New Orleans, undated, color lithograph (Box 5, Folder M191)
    - New Orleans, 1800s, color engraving (Box 37)
    - New Orleans, 1800s, color engraving (Box 37)
    - Nouvelle Orleans/Nueva Orleans in 1851, limited reprodution from 1970, color lithograph (Oversize-folder 38)
      Bird's-eye view, reproduced from original in 1970.
  - Maryland, 29
    - [Baltimore] Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1900s, card photograph (Box 37)
    - [Baltimore] Laying of the first stone of the B & O Railroad, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 6, Folder M193)
      Photograph of a painting, "The Laying of the First Stone of the Baltimore & Ohio Railroad. July 4, 1828," by Stanley M. Arthurs.
    - [Frederick] Mt. Olivet Cemetery, late 1800s, card photograph (Box 37)
      With biographical note on back denoting John Wright and family's burial site in the photograph. Knight was brought back from France to be buried here.
    - Annapolis, Capital of the State, 1838, black-and-white lithograph (Oversize-folder 11)
      Harbor view
    - Baltimore in 1752, limited reproduction from 1967, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 38)
      Reproduced in 1967.
    - Bird's eye view of the city of Annapolis, 1864, limited reproduction from 1967, color lithograph (Oversize-folder 38)
    - City of Baltimore, 1800s, color engraving (Box 37)
    - City of Baltimore, 1830, engraving (Oversize-folder 40)
      View from Federal Hill across the river.
    - Panoramic View of Skyline of Baltimore, MD, undated, color illustration (Oversize-folder 11)
      Long folding postcard, view from body of water.
    - View of Baltimore City, 1850, limited reproduction from 1967, black-and-white lithograph (Oversize-folder 38)
      Reproduced from original in 1967.
    - Washington's Monument, Baltimore, 1800s, engraving (Box 6, Folder M194)
  - Massachusetts, 30
    - Hemenway Gymnasium -- Harvard Summer School of Physical Training -- 1906, 1906, black-and-white photograph (Box 47)
      From the Wilbur Wade Card Papers.
    - William Cullen Bryant home, woodcut (Box 57)
    - [Cambridge] "Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.," 1830 Sept. 1, engraving (Box 6, Folder M198)
      From Georgia Historical Society
    - [Cambridge] "Hemenway Gymnasium - Harvard Summer School of Physical Training - 1906," 1906, black-and-white photograph (Box 6, Folder M198)
    - [Salem] "'House of Seven Gables,' Residence of Nathaniel Hawthorne," undated, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 6, Folder M201)
    - Boston - From the Harbour, undated, lithograph (Box 6, Folder M196)
    - Boston in 1775, undated, lithograph (Box 6, Folder M195)
      From Jones: Biographical Sketches of the Delegates from Georgia to the Continental Congress.
    - Fanueil Hall, Boston, undated, engraving (Box 6, Folder M197)
    - Historical Massachusetts, 1920s-1950s, 6 black-and-white photographs (Box 6, Folder M199.1)
      Courtesy of the Maynard Workshop, Waban, Mass. The Maynard Workshop published images of New England from about 1914-1959.
    - Historical Massachusetts, 1920s-1950s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 6, Folder M199.2)
      Includes exhibit cards. "Courtesy of the Maynard Workshop, Waban, Mass."
    - Longfellow's Home, undated, 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 6, Folder M200)
  - Mediterranean, 31
    - Mediterranean area photographs, 1945-1946, 68 black-and-white photographs (Box 11, Folder M336)
      From the Robert Tracy Zimmerman collection. Includes note about Robert Tracy Zimmerman's travels.
  - Michigan, 32
    - City of Detroit, Michigan, Taken from the Canada shore near the ferry, 1837, color engraving (Oversize-folder 17)
    - [Dearborn] "The Edison Institute Museum and Greenfield Village," undated, 25 souvenir photographs (Box 6, Folder M202)
      Includes case.
    - [Detroit] July 4 parade (?), undated, card photograph (Box 6, Folder M203)
      Corner of Woodward and Jefferson Avenues. Includes descriptive letter regarding the photograph.
  - Mississippi, 33
    - [Biloxi] Life in Biloxi, 1900s, 4 black-and-white photographs (Box 6, Folder M204)
      Lighthouse, schooner race, residence with a palm tree growing through the front steps, and row of moss-draped live oaks.
    - [Mississippi River] "The Jolly Flatboatmen," 1800s, black-and-white photograph of a painting (Box 6, Folder M205)
    - [Oxford] Courthouse, 1963 June, color photograph (Box 6, Folder M207)
    - Home on the Mississippi, 1871, color lithograph (Oversize-folder 41)
    - Natchez homes, 1900s, 7 black-and-white photographs (Box 6, Folder M206)
  - Missouri, 34
    - Report on the St. Louis Tornado, 1927 Sept. 29, album (Box 44)
      Stapled album with typed captions and black-and-white photographs.
  - New Hampshire, 35
    - A view of Portsmouth, late 1700s?, modern reproduction, engraving (Box 37)
  - New Jersey, 36
    - [West Long Branch] Shadow Lawn Mansion, undated, 28 black-and-white photographs (Box 6, Folder M209)
      From Monmouth College Photos.
  - New Mexico, 37
    - A Camera Report on El Cerrito - a Typical Spanish-American Community in New Mexico, 1942 Jan., Irving Rusinow, photographer, album (Box 6, Folder M210)
      This album contains about 75 black-and-white prints with descriptions. Published by U.S. Department of Agriculture.
  - New York, 38
    - [New York] American Tobacco Company Offices (?), 1894 and 1896, 2 card photographs (Box 47)
    - Byant Park, under construction, 1933?, pen and ink sketch (Box 59)
    - Great International Naval Review, 1893, color illustration (Oversize-folder 11)
      Colorful, stylized illustration of boats.
    - New York in 1768, undated, engraving (Box 6, Folder M211)
    - Niagara Falls, 1901 Oct. 16, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 6, Folder M212)
    - Residence of William Cullen Bryant, 1893?, black-and-white engraving (Box 59)
    - View of the Cattskill Mountain House, N.Y., after painting by Thomas Cole, 1800s, black-and-white engraving (Box 58, Folder M1809)
    - West 57th Street, New York, undated, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 46)
      View of Carnegie Lyceum
    - West Point and the Highlands, 1800s, engraving (Box 6, Folder M213)
  - North Carolina, 39
    - ["Teach's Kettle," Bath], circa 1898 (Box 6, Folder M216)
      Long handwritten note on back explaining the story behind the place.
    - [Asheville] Biltmore Estate, circa 1895, black-and-white photo (Box 56)
    - [Asheville] Scenic photographs of Swannanoa River, 1898, 5 black-and-white photographs (Box 61)
      Mounted on cardstock. Roughly 10x22 inches.
    - [Bath] "Souvenir Calender, Ye Old Bath Town, 1705-1905," circa 1906, calendar (Box 37)
      Calendar of 29 black-and-white photographic illustrations.
    - [Bath] St. Thomas Episcopal Church, photographed by T. R. Draper, Bath, NC, 19th century, 3 card photographs (Box 6, Folder M217)
    - [Brunswick] "Ruins of St. Philip's Church," undated (Box 6, Folder M216)
    - [Candor] School in Montgomery County, circa 1900, card photograph (Box 7, Folder M218)
    - [Carthage] "The Cornwallis Tree," undated (Box 6, Folder M216)
    - [Chapel Hill] Caldwell Hall, circa 1935, 7 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M219a)
    - [Chapel Hill] University of North Carolina, undated, 19 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M219)
      Includes original paper case for photographs.
    - [Charlotte] Democratic State Convention, 1908 June 29, postcard (Box 7, Folder M220)
    - [Currituck County] Poplar Branch Township, 1900s, 6 card photographs (Box 37)
    - [Durham] Bennett House, 1876 and undated, 2 lithographs (Box 40)
      One lithograph is glossy.
    - [Durham] "Bennett Place" -- home of James Bennitt, circa 1895-1931, 4 black-and-white photographs, 2 card photographs and 1 postcard (Box 7, Folder M222.1)
    - [Durham] "Bennett Place" -- home of James Bennitt, 1905 and 1900s, 2 card photographs and 1 postcard (Box 7, Folder M222.2)
      Includes a proclamation by North Carolina Governor Thomas J. Jarvis, and a note from the original owner of some of these photographs.
    - [Durham] Bennett Place scenes, undated, 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M223)
    - [Durham] Bennett Place, 1974 Sept. 5, color illustration (Box 40)
      Includes a description of the Bennett House's history.
    - [Durham] Bennett Place, circa 1947 and undated, 2 postcards and 4 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M221)
      All images are of Bennet Place, with the exception of one, a photograph of the bottle Gen. Sherman and Johnston drank while drafting terms for the surrender.
    - [Durham] Blacknall house moving, 1985 June, 23 color photographs (Box 7, Folder M224)
      Note on orig. envelope states that Blacknall house was moved from the corner of Anderson St. and Erwin Road, moved to Alexander St. in Durham.
    - [Durham] Blacknall, William Thomas -- Home, undated, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M225)
    - [Durham] "Campus of Trinity College," 1912-1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 34)
    - [Durham] Civic Center -- Surgeons' Dinner, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M228)
    - [Durham] Commonwealth Cotton Mfg. Co., undated, card photograph (Box 7, Folder M229)
    - [Durham] Commonwealth Cotton Mill Employees, circa 1896, 2 card photographs (Box 40)
    - [Durham] Downtown, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M230)
    - [Durham] Duke Memorial Methodist Church. Men's Bible Class taught by Dr. Hersey Evenette Spence(?), 1900s, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] Duke, B.L. -- Leaf Tobacco Broker, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M231)
    - [Durham] Duke, W. and Son's second Durham factory (1885) with a view of "Fairview" and..., undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] Duke, W. and Sons' Second Durham factory, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] Durham County Courthouse, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
      Photograph is tinted.
    - [Durham] "Fairview," house of Washington Duke, and the first tobacco factory..., undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] "Fairview," Home of Washington Duke, undated, 4 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M232)
      Southeast corner of Main and Duke Streets.
    - [Durham] Durham Female Seminary, 1800s, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] First Graded School, 1883, card photograph (Box 7, Folder M233)
      Given by Miss Carrie Burch of Durham, NC.
    - [Durham] First Presbyterian Church (the First Church) and Manse, undated, black-and-white illustration (Box 7, Folder M234)
      Gift of M.E. Boyd Hamilton.
    - [Durham] Grade School 1889, 1889, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] Graded School in East Durham, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M235)
    - [Durham] High School Class of 1908, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 11)
    - [Durham] "Holy City" Choir, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] Home of Brodie Leonidas Duke, 1883, card photograph (Box 7, Folder M237)
    - [Durham] Home of George Washington Burch, undated, card photograph (Box 7, Folder M226)
      Note on orig. envelope states home stood on corner of West Main and Guess Road, later Buchanan Avenue.
    - [Durham] Home of Washington Duke, undated, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M238)